checkm8.com 2009-04-21

# CheckM8 - Rich Media and Online Ad Technology

**PRIVACY POLICY**

 **

\- Last Updated 7/14/07 -

**

 **Overview**

CheckM8 is committed to the right of Internet consumer privacy. CheckM8 technology services do not require the collection of any personal data from viewers. However, in order to provide the most enhanced end-user experience, CheckM8 utilizes cookies. A cookie is a unique computer identifier that by no means intrudes on the users' anonymity to CheckM8, nor is required for the operation and/or serving of CheckM8 advertisements. The acceptance and removal of cookies is controllable from standard web browsers, whereby users can easily adjust their cookie filtering sensitivity related to CheckM8 due to our P3P-compliance. The following details the principles for the collection and utilization of information by CheckM8 in strict confidence of our online privacy policy: 

**Collection of Internet Consumer Data**

CheckM8 does not collect any personally-identifiable information regarding consumers who view or interact with CheckM8 advertisements (e.g. name, phone number, street address, e-mail address, gender, date of birth, social security number). 

CheckM8 solely collects non-personally identifiable ad delivery and reporting data (Operating System, Type of Browser, Plugins, IP address, page(s) visited, date and time of advertisement viewing and interacting). 

**Use of Internet Consumer Data**

CheckM8 uses collected consumer data information for the sole purposes of providing best suited campaigns fitting user device capabilities and reducing the repetition of advertising via cookie-based reach and frequency capping. 

**Accordance of Internet Consumer Data**

CheckM8 cookie usage and ad delivery and reporting data upholds full compliance to the Network Advertising Initiative definition of Non-Personally Identifiable Information (Non-PII) and the Safe Harbor agreement under Directive 95/46/EC with the European Union. This means that none of the data can be correlated to any individual Internet consumer, and therefore it cannot be applied for profiling purposes. 

**Consumer Advisory on Blocking or Deleting Cookies**

End-users may block or delete cookies stored on your computer. The following information is an informative guideline on how to do so on the majority share of user browsers at this point in time: 

_Step by Step Instructions to Block Cookies on Internet Explorer 6.x or 7.x_ :   
1.Click the Tools button, click Internet Options, and then select the Privacy tab.   
2\. Move the slider completely up to Block All Cookies. On this setting, websites will not be able to store cookies on your computer.   
* Note: Blocking all cookies may prevent you from accessing websites. 

_Step by Step Instructions to Delete Cookies on Internet Explorer 6.x or 7.x_ :   
1.Click the Tools button, click Internet Options, and then select Settings tab.   
2.Select the View Files button.   
3.Select and delete the cookies you want to be removed from your hard drive. 

_Step by Step Instructions to Block Cookies on Firefox 1.x or 2.x_ :   
1.Click the Tools button, click Options, and then select the Privacy tab.   
2\. Unselect "Accept Cookies from Sites”. On this setting, websites will not be able to store cookies on your computer.   
* Note: Blocking all cookies may prevent you from accessing websites. 

_Step by Step Instructions to Delete Cookies on Firefox 1.x or 2.x_ :   
1.Click the Tools button, click Options, and then select the Privacy tab.   
2.Click the “Clear Now” button, select “Cookies”, and then click on “Clear Private Data Now”. 

CheckM8, Inc. reserves the right to modify this privacy policy statement at any time without notice. As such, and for the sake of ease for interested parties to keep up-to-date with the policy, a Last Updated denotation will be clearly posted whenever modified. Please address any questions or concerns to: [privacy@checkm8.com](mailto:privacy@checkm8.com).
